Papish, Nancy; Papers apap144
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Nancy Papish Papers
1953-2001
1970-1994
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap144
11.0 cubic ft. plus 5 map tubes
The papers of Nancy Papish document her involvement with Clearwater, North River Friends of Clearwater (NRFC), and the campaign to stop Hydro-Quebec's development plan for James Bay. These papers document the environmental activism of Nancy Papish from the 1970s through the 1990s. Included are meeting minutes, notes, mailings, press releases, news clippings, magazine articles, programs, and publications. The Clearwater files contain near-complete runs of newsletters produced by both NRFC and the parent Clearwater organization. Evidence of NRFC's outreach activities is found in a slide show titled "This Is Clearwater" and numerous poster displays. Documentation of Clearwater's organization and administration, such as meeting minutes, internal reports, and committee files, are almost entirely absent. There is little information about the membership of Clearwater. The James Bay files contain materials from several organizations.
Biographical Sketch
Nancy Papish, a resident of Schenectady, New York, became involved with environmental activism at a local and regional level in the 1970s. Papish's papers document her involvement with Clearwater, North River Friends of Clearwater (NRFC), and the campaign to stop Hydro-Quebec's development plan for James Bay in northern Quebec.
Clearwater refers to both a boat and an environmental organization of more than 10,000 members. Clearwater's history dates to the late 1960s when folk singer and activist Pete Seeger became interested in building a recreation of the sloops that traveled the Hudson River in the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. The Hudson River Sloop Restoration (HRSR) was the precursor organization, which eventually became Hudson River Sloop Clearwater (HRSC). Its original goal was simply to build the sloop that Seeger envisioned. However, most HRSR members also shared an interest in cleaning up the polluted Hudson River. They decided to use the boat as a "floating classroom", raising public awareness about the need to protect the Hudson by conducting educational sails on the river.
The Hudson River Sloop Clearwater launched in 1969. Today, more than 12,000 people sail on the Clearwater each year. The crew is comprised of paid staff and Clearwater member volunteers. The organization's efforts expanded over the years to include advocating for green space along the river's banks as well as upkeep of the river itself. Clearwater is also well-known for its annual Great Hudson River Revival, a festival of music, arts, and environmental education. [Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. (undated) "About Clearwater". Accessed 27 January 2005, http://www.clearwater.org/about.html].
Founded in the early 1970s, the North River Friends of Clearwater is a sloop club based in the Capital District. Sloop clubs are local organizations that support Clearwater's mission through activities like fundraising and public relations. NRFC, which has an office in downtown Albany, holds monthly meetings regarding sloop issues and works with other local environmental organizations such as the Sierra Club, Save the Pinebush, and the Adirondack Mountain Club on issues of mutual concern. [Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. (undated) "Clearwater Sloop Clubs". Accessed 27 January 2005, http://www.clearwater.org/clubs.html].
Nancy Papish served on numerous committees for the NRFC and played a significant role in coordinating efforts between the Capital Region sloop club and the HRSC parent organization. As an early member of the group, she narrated a slide show that educated the public about Clearwater's mission and was even chosen as a volunteer crew member aboard the sloop in 1978. She brought a wealth of educational skills to Clearwater's activities since her background included three-four years teaching high school English, teaching an undergraduate education class at SUNY Albany, and multiple years working with the National Teacher Corps Project. Papish's recreational skills ran the gamut from canoeing, to sailing, to nautical arts like knot-tying, which made her a valuable addition to Clearwater's efforts. [Nancy Papish Papers. Series 1, Box 2, Folder 8. M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University Libraries, University at Albany, State University of New York].
NRFC was one of many organizations that participated in a grassroots campaign to stop Hydro-Quebec's proposed James Bay II project in the early 1990s. New York State contracted with Hydro-Quebec to purchase electric power through 2018. Hydro-Quebec planned to build several dams in the subarctic James Bay region of Quebec. This enraged environmental and human rights activists, who argued that the dams would destroy an ecosystem on which native Cree and Inuit communities depended. In 1994, the New York Power Authority canceled its final contract with Hydro-Quebec.
May 2009 brought double reasons for celebration as the HRSC family commemorated the sloop's fortieth anniversary and Pete Seeger's ninetieth birthday. Both the sloop and the man responsible for her existence were honored in a concert at Madison Square Garden on May 3, 2009, complete with performers from Dar Williams to Joan Baez. [Art Beat. (30 July 2009). "Pete Seeger's 90th Birthday Blowout on PBS". Accessed 16 Oct. 2009, http://www.pbs.org/newshour/art/blog/2009/07/pete-seegers-90th-birthday-blowout-on-pbs.html]. The Clearwater's trip up the Hudson River to Albany that spring added to the festive atmosphere as she led a flotilla of boats in honor of Henry Hudson's 1609 exploration.
HRSC is also making strides in a new program called the Next Generation Legacy Project, which focuses on green jobs in a green economy for the 21st century. The project will advance in three phases, the first of which began in spring 2009 with the opening of the Clearwater Center for Environmental leadership in Beacon, NY. The ultimate goal is to open eight green cities/green jobs satellite centers in environmental leadership. These will be located all along the Hudson River and will teach children and young adults about renewable resources and a sustainable environment. [Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. (10 Feb. 2009). "Clearwater Announces Next Generation Legacy Project". Accessed 23 September 2009, http://www.clearwater.org/home/535.html].
In honor of its work in the environmental movement, the Clearwater received a place on the National Register of Historic Places in 2004. [Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. (undated). "Clearwater: About us". Accessed 23 Sept. 2009, http://www.clearwater.org/about-us.html].
Scope and Contents
The papers document the environmental activism of Nancy Papish from the 1970s through the 1990s, focusing strongly on her involvement with Clearwater and North River Friends of Clearwater, as well as the campaign to stop Hydro-Quebec from building dams in the James Bay region of Quebec. Included are meeting minutes, notes, mailings, press releases, news clippings, magazine articles, programs, posters, and publications. The Clearwater files contain near-complete runs of newsletters produced by both NRFC and the parent Clearwater organization. Evidence of NRFC's outreach activities is found in a slide show titled "This Is Clearwater" and numerous poster displays.
Most of the Clearwater files contain information that was disseminated widely to members, such as mailings, brochures, and publications. The "Clearwater" series has some documentation of Clearwater's organization and administration, such as meeting minutes and internal reports, though most of the minutes pertain to the parent group HRSC, not North River Friends. There is little information about the membership of Clearwater. Documents pertaining to groups and projects that share Clearwater's interests, but were not produced by Clearwater, make up the majority of the subject files.
Since the campaign to stop development in James Bay was grassroots in nature, the James Bay files contain materials from several organizations. Detail about the structure and history of these organizations is lacking, as well as information about individual participants in the movement.
The papers do not contain much personal correspondence, and biographical information on Papish is equally scarce. Although there are files related to environmental education, there is no documentation of Papish's professional life as an English teacher at Schoharie Central School. There are quite a few subject files pertaining to other environmental groups that Papish supported, as well as groups related to the arts. The collection also features memorabilia, mainly tying in to the Clearwater and its fundraising/awareness activities.
Several collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives provide further information on the environmental issues that were of concern to Papish. For a complete list of collections on the subject of conservation and the environment, see http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/conservation.htm. Of particular note are the records of Environmental Advocates of New York, Sierra Club Atlantic Chapter, Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady, and the Solidarity Committee of the Capital District (APAP-024), which contain files on the campaign to stop Hydro-Quebec's James Bay project.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Clearwater Files, 1965-2000
Series 2: James Bay Activism Files, 1963, 1987, 1990-1994, undated
Series 3: Environmental Education Files, 1970-1986, undated
Series 4: Subject Files, 1968-1994, undated
Series 5: Publications, 1966-1991, undated
Series 6: Photographs and Audiovisual Materials, 1978, 1984, 1989, 1993, undated
Series 7: Memorabilia, undated
Series 8: Oversized Materials - Posters, Displays, and Advertisements, 1973-1975, 1978-1979, 1990-1993, undated
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department Special Collections and Archives, by Nancy Papish in 2002.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Schenectady, New York; Native Americans; Conservation and the Environment; New York (State)--Politics and government; Hudson River (N.Y. and N.J.); James Bay Region; Minutes; Clippings (information artifacts); Posters; Newsletters; Correspondence; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Programs; Files by subject; Notes; Maps; Memorabilia; Video cassettes; Audio cassettes; Papish, Nancy; Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc.; Hudson River Sloop Restoration, Inc.; North River Friends of Clearwater (Sloop); Hydro-Québec; James Bay Hydroelectric Project
- Clearwater Files, 1965-2000; 1; 3.0 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains items related to the boat Clearwater; Clearwater as an organization, including its predecessor organization, Hudson River Sloop Restoration; and affiliated sloop clubs, particularly North River Friends of Clearwater. It includes newsletters, board of directors meeting minutes, membership mailings, catalogs, and educational materials. There is a near-complete collection of programs from Clearwater's annual Great Hudson River Revival, as well as copies of Clearwater's official newsletter, mainly from 1973-1993. This newsletter began publication under the name North River Navigator, then became the Clearwater Navigator in 1978. Administrative files from NRFC are limited and include by-laws, charters, some meeting minutes, and a membership dues receipt book from 1978. NRFC newsletters, spanning from 1976-1993, began as an unnamed publication, then became The Compass in 1982.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Annual Meetings, 1976-1979; Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1975-1977; 1980-1981 (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
  - Artwork & Poetry, 1976; Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, Basic Background, Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1974-1977 (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1978-1985 (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Brochures: Clearwater and the Hudson River, 1986-1989; Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Citizen Activism, 1982 (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Clearwater Activities: Assorted -- Picnics, Films, Clean-ups, 1973-1976; 1992-1994; Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9)
  - Clearwater Activities: Concerts, 1970s-1980s (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 10)
  - Clearwater Activities: Festivals [River, Crafting, etc.], 1976-1978; Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 11)
  - Clearwater Activities: Sailing Participants, 1978 July (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 12)
  - Clearwater Catalog, 1976-1978; Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 13)
  - Clearwater Contacts, Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 14)
  - Clearwater Day Legislation, 1979 (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 15)
  - Clearwater Mission, Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 16)
  - Clearwater Polluter Reports, 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 17)
  - Clearwater Report on Goals, Budget, Repairs, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 18)
  - Clearwater Updates & Weekly Highlights, 1975-1979 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - "Clearwater's Key to Common Hudson River Fishes", 1983 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
  - Coastal Zone Management Plan: New York, 1978 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Clearwater Boat Committee, 1981 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Clearwater Main Office & North River Friends, 1975-1977 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Clearwater Main Office & North River Friends, 1978-1985; Undated (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Crew Volunteer Application & Acceptance Information, 1976; Undated (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Crew Volunteer Application -- Papish, Nancy, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Environmental Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee, 1975-1980; 1985 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 10)
  - Ferro-Cement Sloop Plans: North River Friends of Clearwater, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 11)
  - Ferry Sloop Committee: Clearwater Main Office, 1979 (Box 2 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 12)
  - Ferry Sloops, Inc. --Ferry Tales Newsletter, 1983 February; 1984 June; ca. 1985; 1992 January-1992 September (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - Ferry Sloops, Inc. --Ferry Tales Newsletter, 1992 September-1993 September (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
  - Financial Records: Clearwater Main Office, 1972-1985; Undated (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Fundraising and Membership Drives, 1974-1978; Undated (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Great Hudson River Revival: Committee Meetings & Plans, 1979-1984 (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Great Hudson River Revival: Invitation to Volunteer, 1981 (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Great Hudson River Revival Programs, 1979-1981 (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Great Hudson River Revival Programs, 1983-1986 (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Great Hudson River Revival Programs, 1987-1989 (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9)
  - Great Hudson River Revival Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 3 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 10)
  - Hazardous Waste Disposal, 1980-1983; Undated (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - Hike for the Hudson, ca. 1976 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
  - Hudson River Conservation, 1977-1985; Undated (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Hudson River Fisherman's Association: Westway Debate, 1985; Undated (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Hudson River Sloop Clearwater: Miscellaneous Documents, Main Office, ca. 1979-1984 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Hudson River Sloop Restoration, Inc. By-Laws, Charter, Amendments, 1974; 1976 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Hudson River Sloop Singers, 1992 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Hudson River Slooper's Handy Guide (Crew Manual), 1979; 1982 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Hudson River Sloops: A Brief History, 1970 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9)
  - The Hudson River Valley: A Heritage for All Time -- Dept. of Environmental Conservation, 1979 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 10)
  - Hudson Riverfront Park Project, 1975-1982 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 11)
  - Hudson Riverfront Park Project: Concept Map, Albany to Watervliet, Undated (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 12)
  - Hudson Valley/Hudson River Ad Campaign, 1979 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 13)
  - INFORM: Annual Report With Letter to Pola Yolles, 1984 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 14)
  - INFORM:Tracing a River's Toxic Pollution Case Study (1985) and Letters, 1984-1985 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 15)
  - Island Creek Park, 1991-1992 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 16)
  - Lake Michigan Ferry Sloop Project, Undated (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 17)
  - Legal Documents: North River Friends of Clearwater, 1981-1982 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 18)
  - Litter Day, 1976; 1977 (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981-1983; 1991; Undated (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 20)
  - Multilog Communications Network, 1985 January-1985 April (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 21)
  - Newsletter: Beacon Sloop Club, 1983 February-1985 August (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 22)
    Issues missing.
  - Newsletter: Brooklyn Friends of Clearwater, 1978 April-1980 March (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 23)
  - Newsletter: Central Jersey Clearwater Legacy, 1977 June; 1998 March; 1978 June (Box 4 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 24)
  - Newsletter: Clearwater Navigator, 1977 December; 1978 (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - Newsletter: Clearwater Navigator, 1979-1980 (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
  - Newsletter: Clearwater Navigator, 1981-1983 (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Newsletter: Clearwater Navigator, 1984-1986 (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Newsletter: Clearwater Navigator, 1987-1990 (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Newsletter: Clearwater Navigator, 1991-1993 (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Newsletter: Connecticut Clearwater Club, 1976 August (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Newsletter: Haverstraw Bay clearwater Club, 1977 September (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Newsletter: Hudson-Rondout Sloop Club, 1989 May-1989 October; 1990 January-1990 March; 1992 June (Box 5 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9)
  - Newsletter - New York City Friends of Clearwater and Enviroblurb, 1976-1979; 1985 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - Newsletter:North River Navigator, 1971 September; 1973 June-1974 April (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
  - Newsletter:North River Navigator, 1974 May-1975 January (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Newsletter:North River Navigator, 1975-1976 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Newsletter:North River Navigator, 1977-1978 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Newsletter: Raritan Friends of Clearwater, 1983 June; 1984 April-1984 May (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Newsletter: Staten Island Clearwater Friends, 1977 April (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Newsletter: Ulster county Sloop Club, 1977 January-1977 February (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Newsletter: Yonkers Sloop Club, 1982 September-1985 July (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1976-1979; Undated (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 10)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Administrative Papers, ca. 1976-1981 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 11)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater By-Laws, Undated (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 12)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Charters, 1985; 1987-1988 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 13)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Great Hudson River Revival Booth, 1984; Undated (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 14)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Incorporation Certificate Filing Receipt (photocopy), 1976 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 15)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Meeting Minutes, 1979 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 16)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Membership Dues Receipt Book, 1979-1981 (Box 6 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 17)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Newsletter, (untitled), 1975 December-1982 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Newsletter The Compass, 1982-1989 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
  - North River Friends of Clearwater Newsletter The Compass, 1990-1993 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Notes: Handwritten, Assorted Topics, Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Papish, Nancy: Hudson River Sloop Restoration Donation Receipts, 1975-1977 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Postal Permits and Bulk Mailing, 1978-1979 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1978-1984; Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Pumpkin Sails, 1984; Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Reservation Forms: Educators' Informational Sail, 1978 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9-10)
  - Run for the River, 1980 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 11)
  - Sailing: Basic Information, Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 12)
  - Sailing Lessons, Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 13)
  - Sailing Programs, 1985-1987; Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 14)
  - Sailing Request Form, Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 15)
  - Seeger, Pete: Folklore Films of Pete and Toshi, ca. 1965 (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 16)
  - Seeger, Pete: General Background, Interviews, Photos, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 7 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 17)
  - Sloop Clubs: Members and General Information, 1978-1979; Undated (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 1)
  - Sloop Club Congress, 1975-1981; Undated (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 2)
    (includes 1975 charter).
  - Team-Based Decision-Making Seminar, ca. 1983 (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 3)
  - Traditions Project 1st Edition, 2000 (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 4)
  - Troubled Waters: Toxic Chemicals in the Hudson River, 1977 (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 5)
  - Van Herik, Russell: Opinion Letter -- Clearwater's True Purpose, 1977 (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 6)
  - Walkabout Clearwater Newsletters, 1987-1988 (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 7)
  - Walkabout Clearwater, 1984-1986; Undated (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 8)
  - Water Quality and Standards, 1980 (Box 8 (1-Clearwater Files), Folder 9)
- James Bay Activism Files, 1963; 1987; 1990-1994; Undated; 2; 0.6 cubic ft.
  This series consists of Papish's files on Hydro-Quebec's James Bay project and the efforts of activists to stop the project. It includes news clippings, political cartoons, press releases, meeting announcements and minutes, magazine articles, fliers, brochures, and mailings from organizations involved in the campaign to stop James Bay II. These organizations include P.R.O.T.E.C.T., the James Bay Action Network, the James Bay Defense Coalition, the New York James Bay Network, and the Student Environmental Action Coalition. There are also files with background information on the native populations of Quebec, particularly the Cree and Innu populations.